<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Todor Grudev</title>
    <description>Writing about stuff</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Change the default primary key type in Rails</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Rails had changed the default type of the primary key from &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;int&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;big int&lt;/code&gt; when creating a new table - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rails/rails/pull/26266&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Change Default Primary Keys to BIGINT #26266&lt;/a&gt;, but unless you are working with a big set of records (bigger than 2^31) it’s a waste of resources.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/change-the-defaul-primary-key-type-in-rails/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/change-the-defaul-primary-key-type-in-rails/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Installing Extraterm on Ubuntu 19.10 (Updated)</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;** This is an updated version for Ubuntu 20.04 and extraterm 0.59.2 (current Date is 07.06.2021)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/installing-extraterm-on-ubuntu-19/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/installing-extraterm-on-ubuntu-19/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sidekiq, systemd and Capistrano</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;In this blog post I am going to write about my approach on deploying a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Ruby On Rails&lt;/code&gt; application and dealing with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Sidekiq&lt;/code&gt; (job scheduler written in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Ruby&lt;/code&gt;). This approach is probably suitable for a small/medium application like  &lt;a href=&quot;https://tagrudev.com/2019/outmuscle-me/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Todor Grudev - Outmuscle Me&lt;/a&gt;. I would not recommend following this for a project with a lot of usage, Outmuscle Me at the time of that post has 262 Users, so you can imagine the infrastructure is not really demanding.  Heavy operations like syncing activities with Garmin and Fitbit were actually the reasons I decided to rollout &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Sidekiq&lt;/code&gt; in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 08:10:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/sidekiq-systemd-and-capistrano/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/sidekiq-systemd-and-capistrano/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Road to 10 000 push ups</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2018 I started a physical challenge with a friend of mine, we decided to start doing 50 push ups a day as a way to get in shape, this quickly turned into something more serious and we invited a couple of friends to join. Being a web developer, it was not hard to build something that will keep track of our current progress and in 2019 the &lt;a href=&quot;https://outmuscle.me&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Outmuscle Me&lt;/a&gt; project was born. A lot more people liked the idea and joined our challenge, it evolved into 6 months of doing Push Ups, competing against each other, finding the motivation of doing exercises each day.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/the-road-to-10-000-push-ups/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/the-road-to-10-000-push-ups/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Outmuscle Me</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of months ago I wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://tagrudev.com/2019/the-art-of-push-ups/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Art of Push Ups&lt;/a&gt;, in that blog post I presented a tool that I’ve developed in order to keep track of my training activities. Surprisingly it grew on its own, there are more than 30 active users, not that many, but enough to give me a push to develop it a little bit further.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/outmuscle-me/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/outmuscle-me/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Art of Push Ups</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A push-up (or press-up) is a common calisthenics exercise beginning from the prone position, or the front leaning rest position. They are also a common form of punishment used in the military, school sport, or in some martial arts disciplines.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 20:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/the-art-of-push-ups/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/the-art-of-push-ups/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My 2019 challenge</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Four years ago I decided to start with the the thing called “yearly challenge”, the reason was I had just passed my mid twenties and I felt like it was time to go back and do a retrospective. Time to look at the things I’ve done wrong, could have done better or missed doing. The result / conclusion was that I didn’t really go out of my comfort zone and I needed to change that (reading in my inner voice):&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 20:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/my-2019-challenge/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/my-2019-challenge/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>